PROFESSOR: In general, this family of
heuristics can, kind of, be laid out
in a nice way.
So we can take two heuristics,
say, h a and h c.
If we have these two heuristics and if
it's true that for all nodes n, a is
bigger than c.
So we run them both.
And whatever node I give you, it looks
at the state, it does its computation,
and one heuristic is always
bigger than the other.
We say that h sub a dominates h sub c.
This means that we have a notion
of heuristics being better.
Now some heuristics won't
actually be better.
You'll have h a and you'll have h b.
And sometimes h a is bigger and
sometimes h b is bigger, and so
they're kind of incomparable
in the sense of dominance.
However, we can still talk
about their relation.
We can talk about what's called the
semi lattice of heuristics.
Because we can take two incomparable
things, a and b.
We can take the point-wise max,
which means for any node
n, we find its state.
And then we compute a and we compute
b, and we take the max.
It turns out, the max of immiscible
heuristics is admissible.
And if I take these two different things
a and b and I take their max,
it's going to be dominate them both.
That's easy to see from the
definition of dominance.
So that means we're going to have this
structure where we've got sometimes
you have c, and sometimes you have
something that's just better.
And sometimes you have a and b, but you
can merge them together by maxing
and get something that's
better than either.
And at the top and bottom of this
lattice is something interesting.
We already talked about the top.
There's always, at the top of this
lattice, the best possible heuristic,
which is the exact one.
And we know that's not very useful
because, although it expands few
nodes, it's too expensive to compute.
The bottom of the lattice
is also interesting.
The bottom of the lattice is a heuristic
that always return zero.
OK?
Is it admissible?
Sure.
Is easy to compute?
What happens when you run a star search
and h always return zero?
Yeah, you're ordering things by the f
value of a state, which is the g value
of the state plus the h
value of the state.
But if h is zero, then you're just
working with the g cost, the path
cost, and that's uniform cost search.
So if you ever panic and you can't
come up with a heuristic, you can
always just answer zero and you end
up with uniform cost search.
But it won't speed anything up, and
it's one of the two trivial
heuristics.